So both articles we provided you contain the answer but
كلا المقالتين التي قدمناهما إليك تحتوي على الإجابة
let's just take a look at one of the articles.
ولكن هيا بنا نلقي نظرة على مقالة منهما.
So Joanna's blog post here.
وها هي تدوينة جوانا.
Now in this first section, she explains about audio focus.
في القسم الأول، توفر بعض التفسيرات بشأن تركيز الصوت.
And further down here,
وإضافة إلى ذلك،
she says that you can request the audio focus from the AudioManager class and
تقول أنه يمكن طلب تركيز الصوت من فئة مدير الملفات الصوتية
she provided a link to the method that we can call to request audio focus.
ووفرت رابطًا إلى الوظيفة التي يمكننا استدعاؤها لطلب تركيز الصوت.
So, let's navigate there.
ولذا، هيا بنا إلى هناك.
So, here's the requestAudioFocus method in Android documentation.
هذه وظيفة طلب تركيز الصوت في مستندات توثيق آندرويد.
Now, let's go back to the blog post.
والآن، هيا بنا نعود إلى التدوينة.
In that same sentence, she provides a link on how to release audio focus when
في الجملة ذاتها، وفرت رابطًا عن طريقة إفلات تركيز الصوت
you're done playing the sound.
عند الانتهاء من تشغيل الملف الصوتي.
And that takes us to the abandonAudioFocus method
وهذا ينقلنا إلى وظيفة التخلي عن تركيز الصوت
within the AudioManager class.
في فئة مدير الملف الصوتي.
All right, so we've answered the first two questions so far.
حسنًا، لقد أجابنا عن أول سؤالين حتى الآن.
We can request audio focus from the Android system by calling
يمكننا طلب تركيز الصوت من نظام آندرويد
the AudioManager's requestAudioFocus method and then we can play our audio.
باستدعاء وظيفة طلب تركيز الصوت الخاصة بمدير الصوت ثم يمكننا تشغيل الملف الصوتي.
When we're immediately done playing audio, we can release audio focus
عند الانتهاء مباشرة من تشغيل الملف الصوتي، يمكننا إفلات تركيز الصوت
by calling the abandonAudioFocus method in the AudioManager class.
باستدعاء وظيفة التخلي عن تركيز الصوت في فئة مدير الصوت.
Now note that these two methods do have input parameters that you'll need to
والآن لاحظ أن هاتين الوظيفتين لديهما معلمات إدخال ستحتاج إلى المرور فيها،
pass in, but you can shove that in the documentation later when we actually
ولكن يمكنك عرض هذا قي مستندات التوثيق في وقت لاحق
need to use these methods.
عندما نكون بحاجة حقيقية إلى هذه الوظائف.
All right, so on to the third question of what callback should we implement so
حسنًا، بالنسبة للسؤال الثالث المتعلق ما الرد الذي يجب تطبيقه
that we can get notified when the audio focus changes for our app?
كي نتمكن من جلب الإشعارات عندما يتغير تركيز الصوت للتطبيق؟
An example of this case is,
مثال على هذه الحالة،
if a phone call comes in then we need to adjust our audio playback accordingly.
إذا جاء اتصال هاتفي ونحن بحاجة إلى ضبط تشغيل الملف الصوتي حسب ذلك.
Now back in the bog post in the same paragraph, it explains the system
والآن بالعودة إلى التدوينة في الفقرة ذاتها،
may need to temporarily or permanently take the audio focus away from our app.
يوضح الشرح أن النظام قد يحتاج إلى إخراج تركيز الصوت من التطبيق بصورة مؤقتة أو دائمة.
And so for that we need to create an instance
ولذا نحن بحاجة إلى إنشاء نسخة من
of the OnAudioFocusChangeListener to listen for
OnAudioFocusChangeListener للاستماع إلى
these changes on the device so that we can react to them.
هذه التغييرات في الجهاز ومن ثم يمكننا التفاعل معها.
So let's navigate to the OnAudioFocusChangeListener interface.
هيا بنا ننتقل إلى واجهة OnAudioFocusChangeListener.
So OnAudioFocusChangeListener is another interface
ولذا فإن OnAudioFocusChangeListener يعد واجهة أخرى
just like other interfaces that we've used.
مثل الواجهات الأخرى التي استخدمناها من قبل.
Like OnClickListener and the media players OnCompletionListener interface.
مثل واجهة OnClickListener وواجهة OnCompletionListener.
So notice that it contains one abstract method that we'll need to implement.
ولذا لاحظ أنها تحتوي على وظيفة مجردة وسوف نحتاج إلى تطبيقها.
So we need to provide code on what to do when the audio focus changes.
ولذا نحن بحاجة إلى توفير الكود فيما تفعله عند حدوث تغيير لتركيز الصوت.
So for example, if we lose audio focus we should probably
على سبيل المثال، إذا فقدنا تركيز الصوت
stop playing the pronunciation of the word in our app.
فربما علينا إيقاف تشغيل نطق الكملة في التطبيق.
And we can figure out the details of how to handle audio focus changes later.
ويمكننا التعرف على تفاصيل كيفية التعامل مع تغييرات تركيز الصوت في وقت لاحق.
All right, so back to the third quiz question.
حسنًا، وبالعودة إلى السؤال الثالث من الاختبار.
In order to be notified of changes in audio focus,
من أجل أن يتم إخطارنا بالتغييرات التي تطرا على تركيز الصوت،
we need to create an OnAudioFocusChangeListener.
يجب علينا إنشاء OnAudioFocusChangeListener.
And then we need to implement the onAudioFocusChange callback method.
ثم علينا تطبيق وظيفة رد onAudioFocusChange.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
[BLANK_AUDIO]